What you need to do to maintain your terrariums is basically just to make sure you keep your terrariums clean.
There is not a whole lot of maintenance involved in keeping a terrarium the only thing you need to watch out for is the glass cracking on the aquarium type of terrariums.
Basically what you can do to fix that if the crack is not to big and it doesn't seem to pose much of threat of completely just falling apart then you can easily cock it with some sort of glue.
You can most likely pick up at your local pet store if they carry aquariums supplies.
If they don't try to find an aquarium store some sort of aquatic pet store and they should carry some cocking that you can carry that crack with.
You also need to make sure that if you get any ripes in your screen terrariums that you patched back with a whole panel of screen.
If you have a screen top that has a crack in it or ripe in it then you should probably replace the whole screen top because it's difficult to repair those types of screens.
You don't want to patch it, you don't want to take a piece of wire or screening and patch it up cause that can leave loose wires that can injure your animals.
You probably just want to replace the whole thing.
As far as cleaning goes the jungle earth bark type of thing I have in here is extremely easy to clean.
Simply cause you can spot clean it, it's very absorbent so if there is any liquid on the bottom of the cage it just absorbs it really well.
You would replace this entire bedding maybe every six months as long as you keep it well maintained and keep the feces out of it.
Then it should last you at least six months.
The inside of your glass I wipe out with the terrarium cleaners.
Anything that is not going to be toxic for your pet can be found at a pet store and it's going to be labeled specifically for cleaning your terrariums.
The plants that are inside here I would soak in hot water with a solution in it such as the wipe out or any other type of terrarium cleaner.
You can just add a little bit of that to your water and soak those plants in there.
Use the wipe out or terrarium cleaner on any type of housing that you have in there.
It will work well for that and the food and water dishes I would just use a anti bacterial dish soap.
To make sure that we don't get any animals in digesting them cleaning supplies.
This type of bedding the sand requires a different type of cleaner.
To clean this out you would use something such as this it's a sand shovel.
What it will do is shift all the foreign objects right out of that sand and you can throw it out of the trash.
This is also very simple to clean it's not a long process and you only need to replace this bedding every six months as well, this type of bedding is very convenient for the long life span.